Yeah!
耶 了
On the 15th of May, in the jungle of Nool,
五月十五这一天 在兼宁里的某个角落
in the heat of the day, in the cool of the pool,
夏日炎炎，在清泳的水池和里
he was splashing, enjoying the jungle's great joys,
大和象荷顿正在玩水 享受灶补生活最棒的时刻
when Horton the Elephant heard a small noise.
这时他突然职到一个细微的者音
-Horton!
一荷顿!
Good morning, class. Are you ready?
早，同学们，准人备上课了?
-Yeah! -Jump on board!
-对1! 一那就上来吧 !
Look out below!
下面的注意嗓!
Tommy's on board. Katie, you there?
汤米上来了，误蒂，栋呢?
Okay.
很好
There it is.
就是那个
This is one of the jungle's most amazing creatures, the leaf bug.
这是业宁守最奇特的生物之一 气莱器
In order to protect itself from predators, it disguises itself as a leaf.
为了让自己不被掠食者叶掉 秽们会偏装成一片片的全子
This one's got quite a grip. Come on, little buddy.
这个小像伙有哑国执 来吧，小像伙
Don't be shy.
别害姜嘛
I guess I was mistaken, kids.
我想我可能和弄钳了
There are obviously no leaf bugs in this area. Even if...
很明普地，这里根本没有气莱器
No, they're on me!
息们在我身上 !
I think I swallowed one!
我好像吸到一焦了 !
Tommy! Pull it out!
泛米 ! 把物抓出来 !
Uh, okay.
好吧
Then humpfing a "humpf" was a sour Kangaroo,
哼哼叫的是售壕脾所的袋饼
the type who's convinced she knows better than you.
她自以为自己扰所不知
She made every law and enforced every rule
她制订规矩也才行法律
as self-proclaimed head of the jungle of Neal.
以努震森补的领导者自居
Why can't I play with the other kids, Mom?
为什么我不能和其他小孩玩?
How many times have I told you that
我说过，在娄林守
the jungle is no place to act like a wild animal.
言行绝不能像焦野生动物
My, that Horton certainly is eccentric.
那个叫荷顿的膛真是个怪脸
And the children are learning so much from him.
筷子们从他身上学到很多东西
Learning to be a bunch of harebrained half-wits!
学会怎订变成一群愚蠢的策蛋 !
And that's why my Rudy is pouch-schooled.
所以我的小袋筷都由我亲自教育
So while Kangaree stood there, - sneering a sneer...
就在袋秘杂杂冷别热吝的时候…
Horton, that was the best time I've ever had in my life!
荷顿，今天真是太精采了 !
..once again, the speck floated right by Horton's ear.
…那粒小灰庆再度习过荷顿的耳劳
Then he heard it again, just a very faint yelp,
他又孤到一个极为细小的声音
as if some tiny person were calling for help.
匠来像是个很小的生物在求救
And you know what he thought?
你知道他怎订想吗 ?
Why, he thought that there must be someone
他认为在那一粒小小的微靡上
on top of that small speck of dust!
一定有人 !
Or even a family, it just might be so,
或许是一家人“，很有可能
a family with children just starting to grow.
一个有效个芒子要疼的家庭
I want to live!
我想活下去 !
I gotta go. Katie, you're in charge!
我先网了，弓蒂，换接手 !
Wait!
等一等 !
-Come back! -Watch it!
一回来! 一小心点 !
One more! One more! One more!
再一根!再一根 ! 再一根!
-l hear someone coming! -Give me those!
一我匠见有人靠近 ! 一香蕉给我 !
-Wait! -Sound the alarm!
一等一等 ! 一快拉警报 !
Excuse me. Pardon my stampede!
原花我的大象腿 !
Sorry, Wickershams! I promise I'm gonna clean all this up later!
抱歉，猴子家族 我等一下会来扣忙整理 !
Bring the ammo!
把弹药拿来 !
I love the smell of bananas in the morning.
早晨的香蕉味引我心旷神愉
Banana in the hole!
香蕉炸弹发射!
Come on, guys! We're all mammals!
别人这样 ! 我们都是哺乳闫耶 !
I feel the diplomatic process is beginning to break down.
我想外交策略完全没用
There you are! I got you!
你在这里，我接住你了 !
Hi, kids!
你好，和芒子们
Wow.
好险
There.
好了
Now you're safe.
这下你安全了
I know I heard you say something. I just know it.
我确定我职到你说了些什么 我很确定
Where are you?
你在哪里?
Horton!
荷顿 !
Sorry!
对不起
I just... There was this speck, and it called out for help.
都是这粒小灰庆啦 ! 它向我求救
-And I was... -The speck called out for help?
一 我就… 一这粒小灰麻向你求救2?
Well, not the speck. I mean, that's ridiculous.
不是灰庆在求救咬，那太扯了
Is that what you thought I meant? No, the speck can't call out for help.
娩以为我是那个意思嘱? 灰庆怎订可能会求救
Come on, get real.
拜认，列前了
No, there's a tiny person on that speck that needs my help.
是灰靡上的小小人需要我帮助
Absurd. There aren't people that small!
乱计，根本没有那麻小的人 !
Well, maybe they aren't small.
可能闪不是他们小
-Maybe we're big. -Horton.
一也许是我们比较大 一荷上顿
No, really, think about it. What if there was someone way out there
个细想想，要是真有人正在那上面
looking down on our world right now?
低头看著我们的世界
And to them, we're the specks.
对他们来说，我们就是灰靡
And then, maybe someone else will come along and say,
这了时有人这
“Oh, there can't be people that small", and the first guy would say,
“根本没那麻小的人” 第一个人就这
“Are you calling me a liar?”
“你是访我这议2?”
And the second guy would say, “If the shoe fits, wear it!"
另一人就这 : “敌府议就要承认”
And now the fists are flying, and the first guy picks up a brick,
接著两个人打了起来
and you might want to zip up the pouch for this next part.
接下来的对话小孩子不大送合区
“All right, fat boy, you want some of this..."
“死胖子，你入捷吗?”
-Horton! -What?
一荷顿! 一怎样 ?
There is nothing on that speck.
那粒灰靡上什么都没有
-But I heard. -Did you?
一可是我匠到了 一你有吗 ?3
Really? Oh, my.
真的?3 天哪
Then how come I don't hear anything?
那为什么我什么也没隐到?
Well...
这个嘛…
If you can't see, hear or feel something,
看不到、贡不到或感觉不到
it doesn't exist.
那东西就绝对不存在
And believing in tiny, imaginary people
和还有相信那些幻想出来的小小人
is just not something we do or tolerate,
在努需森补这个地方
here in the jungle of Nool.
是我们不该做，也不会容忍的事
Really? Because I bet if I really tried, I could find somebody who'd believe
是吗? 可是我敢这只要我去试 我一定可以找到
-what I've been saying. -You will do nothing of the sort.
一原意相信的人 一你什和麻也不阁做
You will not breathe a word of this lie to anyone else, especially the children.
不准你对任何人这这乱聊的谎言 特别是对小孩子
I do not want you poisoning their minds with this nonsense.
不准用人这些议言毒害他们的心志
Our community has standards, Horton.
我们的社区可是有规范的，荷顿
If you want to remain a part of it, l recommend you follow them.
如果你膛想继续待下去 我鞠你还是遵守规范
Have a nice day.
说你今天愉快
All right, then, I'll take that under advisement.
好吧，我会好好思考你这的话
I don't understand. I know I heard you.
真搞不懂，我明明就有欧到啊
It was as plain as the nose on my face.
声音很明显从我面前杜过去
That's it. Maybe you can't hear me.
对了，也许你聘不到我
Of course! Your ears must be tiny. I need to speak up.
当然路，你们的耳采一定也很小 所以我要大玫点
Hello!
哈唆!
Now some people out there, l think l know whe,
有些动物…我想我知道有锥
may find they agree with that sour Kangaroo.
或许也会认同刻薄的袋鼠嫣媚
"There can't really be people as small as a mite."
认为不可能有纵枉子一样小的人
Well, there can, and there are, because Horton was right.
或许有可能…真的有…: 因为荷顿这对了
Hello!
哈唆!
That single "hello" traveled all the way down
这一声“哈唆”一路传下来
to the speck, through the clouds, until it found a small town.
进入灰应，穿过了云层 直到传到了这座小镇
A town known as Whoville, for there lived the Whos,
这和里叫呼呼镇，呼呼族就住这
feeling happy and safe, knowing only good news,
平安快乐过活，只知道好消息
unaware that their world was a speck ona clover,
不知道自己的世界只是一粒灰庆
unaware that the sweet life they knew might be over.
也没发现快乐的生活正面呈危险
-Over! -Under!
一束过 ! 一名过 !
The Mayor of Whoville, aman named McDedd,
呼呼镇的镇綦名叫奏克当奈德
was devoted and fair and a little bit odd.
做事认真又正直，只是有骂乱厘头
The Mayor and his wife, they had children to spare,
人镇长夫妇有一群孩子要照顾
96 daughters, some here and some there.
九十六个女儿 有些坐在这祷、有些坐在那里
96 girls to love, 96 girls to teach,
有九十六个女儿要爱 有九十六个女儿要教
but the Mayor had only a few seconds for each.
不过镇长只能给每个女儿天秒馆
Daddy, I got better than best on my Who-story test.
爸备 ! 我呼呼族历史考试满分
Who-story. l remember it well.
呼呼族历史，我最熟了
That's one of my girls.
真是我的好女儿
-Hildy's been using my hairbrush! -Holly's been using my hairbrush!
一海达偷用我的梳子 ! 一荷莉才偷用我的梳子 !
Look! Over there!
快看那焉 !
There. All better.
好多了
Can I please have a Who-phone, Dad? Everyone else in my class has one.
能换我买一支呼呼手机吗 ? 我们班上每一个同学都有
Oh, really? Everyone?
是吗? 每个都有?
I will think about it.
我会好好考卡的
Daddy, look! Daddy, look!
和爸，快看! 符，快看!
Toof.
牙“此”
It's a "T-H", sweetheart. It's "tooth."
是牙“郊”，亲爱的，要担舌
In Whoville tradition, unlike yours or mine,
呼呼族的传统，和你我的不同
the Mayor's oldest is next in the Mayoral line.
他们镇长的职位由长子代代相传
And whe was the oldest? To lead and stand tall?
奴是长子? 接下这家的棒子?
lt was JoJo, his son, the smallest Whe of all.
和在和奋，他儿子，最绑小的一个
So, JoJo, what's shaking? What's happening? What's the word?
说吧，备乔，你今天好不好? 发生了什么事?3 有什么新闻 ?
Now, to you or to me, it's abundantly clear
相信现在你我都非常清楚
that JoJo did not want his father’s career.
备备根本不想接他父亲的职务
But the Mayor pressed forward, completely deluded,
只见镇长一肩情愿的构思计划
while JoJo just sat there in silence and broeded.
和在在御若有所思的坐在那里
Oh, JoJo!
和在在 !
-Hey, why does he get more time? -That's not fair.
一为什么他的时间比较长? 一不公平
Son! Hey!
儿子 !
And why didn't he speak?
他为什条不访话呢?
Well, 1 think that the lad was afraid if he did, he might let down his dad.
我想他是怕访了会让他和葡难过
You know what's awesome?
你知道什条最正点吗?
This is awesome.
这些就很正黑
Just look at the men and women hanging on these walls.
看看这些糙壁上的祖先肖像
You, my boy, are part of a family legacy that spans centuries.
你，乖儿子 你是百年家族像出善英的一份子
You know what? Your grandfather was Mayor of Whoville,
知道吗 ? 你过和曾是呼呼镇镇其
and your great-grandmother, that's right,
和还有你的曾曾祖耳，没有钳
all the way down to your
现在来看看这一路
great-great-great-great-not-so-great-
伟大的…仿大的…伟大的… 没那魔伟大的
great-great-great-great-great-great- great-great-great-great-
伟大的…伟大的…伟大的 曾曾曾…
grandfather.
祖父
Someday I hope to join them.
我希望有一天能加入他们
Be one of the greats.
成为家族的伟大善英之一
I tell you, JoJo, there is nothing like being Mayor.
我告诉你，和在在 没有比当镇长更避的了
I get to sign resolutions, approve ordinances, submit budgets,
批准法条、核准预算
and in the Edible Parade, I'm the one sitting on top of the giant meatball.
而且在美食嘉年革会上 超级大肉世上坐的一定是镇长
Someday, that can be you, too, JoJo.
有一天坐在上面的也会是你
Someday you'll be the one wearing the Mayoral Crest.
有一天你也会别上人镇长徽章
You just... You just need to...
你只要…你只需要…
You know what I mean?
你慌我的意思吗 ?
Okay. Good chat.
好吧，聊天愉快
I'm glad that we had this talk
我很高村我们谈了这魔多
that I'm continuing now by myself. Good.
接下来我就挤给自己匠吧，也好
There. That ought to be comfy.
好了，很舒服吧
Nothing wrong with this, Morton. Nothing wrong with this.
不要放在心上，摩登 一点也不用担心
Just you, me and the speck, shooting the breeze.
只有你我和小灰应，一起聊天
We're a club. We're a group. We can take a vote on the issues.
我们同国的 高横的话，膛可以办个公投
We can be a secret society that controls the balance of power in the world.
也能摘秘密组织，维访世界和平
-Horton. -And no one else can join,
一荷上顿 一难都不能加入
unless they wear funny hats.
除非他头戴怪避
Listen, Horton!
荷上，隐好 !
The Chair recognizes Brother Morton.
我的兄弟摩登是当然会员
lam really happy you found this speck and all,
我很高村你找到人这个小灰麻
but you might want to think about keeping it to yourself.
不过你最好不要让别人知道此事
What? Why?
什条 ? 为什么?
Well, you're talking to a clover. That doesn't look good.
因为你对著一支花讲话 正常人不会这样
You know what doesn't look good?
你知道有问题的是谁?
You talking about the speck like the speck isn't even there.
你的已所好像这灰庵完全不存在
The speck never said anything bad about you.
人家可没有在你背后这你壤话
But, hey! Good luck with your illusion of superiority.
不过这普现了你的幻想力很强
You know, the speck can think anything it wants about me. It's a speck.
它爱怎麻想我随便它 它只是一粒灰大
I see what's going on here.
我知道你在不更什么了
Morton, no matter how tight the speck and I get,
摩登，不管我和人这料灰麻多要好
the speck could never replace you.
它永下也取代不了你
I'm only sad that I would have to explain that, at this point.
我以为我不用解释你就会明白
Well, that's awesome, Horton. That really helps.
你真欧朋友，荷顿
Just try to keep this to yourself.
列把秘密告诉列人
I'll see you later. Try.
竺会儿见吧，列妃广话
Hey, Horton! What you got there?
荷顿，你手上拿的是什么 ?
What? Nothing!
什么?哪有?
We're not doing anything.
我们什么也没做啊 !
-We're totally alone. -Who's "we"?
一我们没有…根本没人? 一“我们”是锥?
“We"? What? "We"? Did I say that? I just... Oh.
什么 ? 我们 ? 我刚有久吗 ?
No, I would never say that, because that would imply that
没，那样这就代表我和锥在一起
I was with someone, and not alone.
不是只有一个人
Okay, seriously, you can't tell anybody. I mean it.
我说真的，这绝对不能这出去
If anybody finds out about this, it could be very, very bad.
要是这秘密被人发现 事情会变得非常非常帮
I'm not sure why.
我也不大明白是为什么
We won't tell anyone.
我们绝对不会这
And if we do, we'll tell them not to tell anyone.
要是我们府了 我们也会叫他们不要跟别人访
Perfect!
太好了
Okay, I'm taking a bath, right,
好，我本来正在洗澡
‘cause my skin gets kind of dry and a little bit ashy.
因为我的唐质偏乾…
While Horton came clean about the speck that he'd found
当荷上顿详细这明他如何找到灰靡
and how he had saved it when it nearly drowned,
导如何椰救它免庆被淖没命运时
the Mayor set off on his morning commute
镇其也正好准备出发去上班
and noticed things weren't quite the same on his route.
叭然他发现好像有哑怪怪的
But please don't blame Horton, for he didn't know that a small bump above...
但是请别怪界荷顿 他根本不知道，上面一个小碰撞…
..and I dove in the water like this!
…我就往水里跳下去
.. was a big bump below.
…会造成下面的大地震
Hey, Joe, don't work too hard.
阿备，不要太拼命了
These luxury condos, they don't build themselves.
豪革地实又不会自己萃好
Hey, look at that! I guess they do build themselves.
真的假的1 它自己鞭好了耶 !
Okay, that happened.
好吧，那也没什科
Now, the Mayor knew it was his job to convey the unusual things
人镇其知道他负责的工作 就是要报告每天发现的愤状
that he'd noticed that day, but there was one problem.
不过问题是
Though his will was strong...
芍然他有强烈预感…
-You're late. -Thank you, Miss Yelp.
一你肥到了 一廊巴炊了，葬波小姐
. nothing in Whoeville had ever gone wrong.
…但是呼呼镇看来一切都很正常
We have all that we need. We need all that we've got.
该有的我们都有
We like it in Whoville. We like it a lot!
我们都爱呼咋镇，住了不想走
We're all very busy with the Who-Centennial coming up,
大家都忙著准简 呼呼镇即兰到来的百年庆
so let's bring this meeting to order.
所以请遵照会议程序进行
Mr. Mayor, I presume you have some good news for us.
镇长先生，我想你有好消息要这
Well, it's news.
是有个消息啦
I don't know if we need to go labeling it “good" or "bad" or anything like that.
到底算是好消息还是壕消息
The thing is, I have noticed some odd goings-on in Whoville lately.
事情就是… 我发现镇上出现了一些怪现象
Good "odd goings-on"?
是好的怪现象吗 ?
Well, you know, tremors, clouds swirling in the sky.
这个嘛…地震、天上旋转的去
And it seems to me, just to be safe,
在我看来，为了安全起见
we might want to consider postponing the Who-Centennial.
也许可以考卡延后呼呼镇百年庆
Consider what?
考虑什么?
Postponing the Who-Centennial.
酶后虎虎百年再
What? Speak up, man!
大志一囊 !
Postponing the Who-Centennial! All right?
延后呼呼镇百年庆 ! 可以吗?
We are about to celebrate 100 years of Whoville happiness and harmony,
全体镇民正忙著庆祝 呼呼镇百年来幸福和谐的日子
and you want to postpone the celebration?
而你竟然想延后这场活动?
Well, what if Whoville’s not safe?
要是呼呼镇不安全呢 ?
Nothing ever goes wrong in Whoville,
呼呼镇从来没有出过差错
never has and never will, you blathering boob!
从前没有，未来也不会有 你这个乱七入莉的策蛋
The Who-Centennial will proceed as planned!
呼呼镇百年庆照计划进行
The Mayor was merely being an idiot.
人镇其只是一时短路秀吉
It will be all smiles from now on.
从现在起请记得笑品常开
That hurt!
噢!噢1会痛!
Girl, got 15,000 friends already.
小姐，我的点阅率早破百葛了
What? What do you mean, it don't look like me?
件和亡叫照片不像?
That looks just like me 10 years ago. Wait a minute. Hold on for a second.
那照片绝对是我 ! 十年前的我，等等，先列持
Treats me like an idiot. 1 am not an idiot.
居然这我是策蛋，我才不是策蛋
Do I look like an idiot?
我看起来像策蛋吗 ?
-You don't want me to answer that. -l am not an idiot.
一你不会想阴到答案的 一我不是策蛋
Has the nerve to call me a boob? I would never call somebody a boob.
竞敢叫我策蛋? 我不会蚊人是策蛋
He's a boob! Look at you.
他才是策蛋，你看看你
Yuck!
咀心!
Look at your face.
看到你那张脸
And I bet you don't look so good with a stapler in your head!
我让你吵吵被叮满头包的滋味
Whoa! Whoa.
咬 !咬
-Thank you, Miss Yelp. -You're welcome.
一谢了，病波小姐 一列客气
Hello?
哈唆?
Who said that? Back off! I'll punch you!
走开 ! 不然我岳遍你 !
Hello.
哈唆
Who's there?
你是谁啊?
This is the Mayor.
我是镇长
The Mayor? The Mayor!
镇其?镇长 !
I'm talking to the Mayor!
我在跟镇长这话耶 !
I knew it. I knew it. I knew it. I knew there was life on this speck.
我就知道有人住在这粒灰麻里
“This speck"? What speck?
灰庆? 什么灰麻啊?
Well, I don't exactly know how to tell you this, but...
我不大知道该怎订告诉你，但是…
You're living on a speck.
你住在一粒灰谭里
Well, l hate to disagree with you, O voice from the drainpipe,
不是我想吐你楼啦 ! 排水管里的老兄
but I live in Whoville.
但是我住在呼呼镇
Right.
才怪
Okay, seriously, who is this?
不要关了“，你到底是谁?
Is this Burt from accounting?
你是会计部的伯特?
No. This is Horton. I'm an elephant.
鱼，我叫荷顿，我是焦大象
Okay, “Horton.”
好吧，荷顿
Fake name. Where are you?
真爱演，你在哪啊?
Well, from where you're standing, f guess I'm in the sky.
从你站的位置来看 我猜我是…在天空上吧?
Compared to you, I'm enormous.
纵你比起来，我超大的
Which is saying something, because I've slimmed down quite a bit.
不过我已经瘦了很多
Your whole world fits on a flower in my world.
你的世界就在我们的一采花上
Oh, man, this is even pushing it for you, Burt.
伯特，你讲的冷笑话比我鞍冷
Don't believe me? Watch what happens when I put you in the shade.
看我把你放在除影下会怎样 ?
This is absolutely impossible...
根本就不会怎样…
Dark.
天黑
Light.
天亮
Light. Dark, light, dark, light, dark, light, dark.
天亮、天黑、天亮、天黑
Don't you see?
看到没?
We're in the middle of some kind of - - amazing cosmic convergence.
我们在神奇的机缘巧会中相遇
Two vastly different worlds, miraculously crossing paths!
雨个完全不同的世界 出乎意料交会在一起
Mine, colossal! Yours, miniscule.
我这殉有和锡大，你那殉有锡小
Yet somehow we've managed to make contact.
而我们居然能搭上缘
if you think about it, it's pretty amazing.
仔细想想，这真的很神奇
Is everything okay down there?
你们那殉都没事吧 ?
I don't know. You tell me. You're the one holding the speck.
你访啊 ? 我们的世界在你手上 !
I'm the one holding the speck.
你们的世界在我手上
Don't you worry, Mr. Mayor.
你不用推心，镇长先生
Hold, please!
先等我一下
What did all of this mean? The Mayor hadn't a clue.
这是怎订回事? 镇长一头圳水
So he ran to the office of Dr. Larue, the brainiest brain on the staff at Whe U.
所以他跑进拉重博士的办公室 她是呼呼大学里最隐明的博士
Dr. Larue!
拉重博士 !
This is crazy.
我大概是首了
Mr. Mayor.
人镇长先生
How may I be of assistance?
有莫魔需要我服务吗 ?
I don't know. Hey, you know, I was just wondering
我不知道，我想问你一件事
if our world were, say, a tiny speck floating through space,
如果我们的世界 是一奏飘在空中的小灰状
how would we know?
我们怎订知道?
Well, why would you ask something like that?
为什么你会周这种问题?
No reason. No reason at all. I don't even remember.
没事，我都忘记我周什么了
Yes, 1 do. You know what?
对，我是问了
Some guy was talking to me.
其实是有人告诉我的
Not an elephant in the sky. A guy on the ground.
不是什条天空里的大象，是那居
There would be several ramifications.
本来就有成千上葛征可能
Good ramifications?
是好的“可能”吗?
A tiny speck?
一粒小灰麻?
Yeah. Tiny speck.
对，小灰庆
Well, we'd have inexplicable tremors, dramatic changes in the weather,
最近是有一些扰预警的地震 气候上也有不寻常的释化
and if we didn't eventually achieve some sort of stability,
如果我们没准法稳定这个世界
our world would be destroyed!
我们可能就会面临…世界末日!
Destroyed? Destroyed. Oh, destroyed.
世界未日?3 世界末日
Horton!
荷顿 !
No, this is Benny.
不，我是…阿赛
Horton is busy right now.
荷顿他现在正在忙
No. I'm joking.
开玩笑的啦 !
We're doomed.
我们完了
Listen, Horton, turns out I need your help a little bit.
荷顿，我想我需要你帮点小屏
Apparently, if that speck keeps moving around,
很明普地，要是这痊小灰庵乱箭
our whole world could be obliterated.
我们的世界可能就会毁沽
Sol need you to find us Whos a safer, more stable home,
所以我需要你帮我们找一个
and fast.
要快
No problem, Mr. Mayor. Let's see...
没周题，镇长先生，我看看…
Wow, that's a nice view.
那里视野真好
Hello. Is everything okay?
一切都没问题吧?
What's going on up there?
上面怎订了2?
This entire jungle is a house of death!
这壬和节直是生死一瞬间现场版 !
Oh, wait. There's a good spot.
等等，那里看来不鳝
And it's then Horten saw at the top of Mount Nool,
就在此时，荷顿看到努震山顶
a small cave that looked peaceful and quiet and coal,
有个看来宁静祥和又酷的小山洞
where a sunflower grew proud and tall from the ground.
一柔向日葵高高盛开在洞穴里
There, he knew every Whe would be safe, would be sound.
他知道呼呼族到了那庄 绝对会平安殷事
I found it, Mayor. The perfect place.
我找到了，镇苹，最完美的地点
Right up there,
就在那上面
-on the top of Mount Neal. -Mr. Mayor?
一那座山顶上 一镇长先生
l wish you could...
我希望你能…
Shiny.
亮码强
The Who-Centennial Committee is waiting for you
呼呼镇百年庆委员会正在等你
to look over the giant meatball for the Edible Parade.
勘验美食敌行要用的超级肉允
And then you're due at the dentist for your Who-root canal.
接著你要找牙医做呼呼根管治疗
You know, sticking "Who" in front of everything doesn't make it hurt less.
在根管治疗前加上呼呼的名性 治疗时六不会比较舒服
Just wastes time!
那是浪费时间
I don't want to go.
我才不要去
Listen, Horton, I've gotta go.
荷顿，我先走了
Apparently, there's a problem with the giant meatball.
我得先去让理那颗超级大肉九
You just take care of that meatball, sir, and leave the freaking out to me.
您全管去处理那栖肉丸吧
So then Horton began his long, perilous trek,
荷顿展开危机重重的长途旅程
determined to save the small world on the speck.
他沁心振救灰应上的小小世界
Horton was faithful and stalwart and kind.
荷顿抱著芭定信念疏仁琵的心
I got you.
我抓好你了
I'll protect you!
我会保护你
.at least in his mind.
…至少他心里是这磨想的
We must become invisible. Travel silently.
我们得小心访愤，悄悄的前进
For there are forces that would seek to destroy us.
因为天人搞不好正要暗算我们
So you think you can sneak up on me, huh?
你以为你偷闵得了我?
It is clear that you are no match for my technique.
矣然你的功夫跟我差速了
I see you have mastered the way of the snapping branch. Watch me tumble!
你还真会用暗器来偷闽啊 看我的前空翻 !
Morton Mouse, go!
屡天和鼠摩登 !
You are fast, Horton, but the Kangaroo has monkeys.
荷顿，真便落 可是袋拨妈妈有猴子军力
I will make monkeys of these monkeys. It is their destiny.
我会好好教训这和群委猴子 这是我们的使命
More clover!
象派气功
Horton is the greatest hero of them all!
荷顿是全世界最停大的英雄 !
-Horton! -Morton!
一荷顿! 一摩登 !
Go!
上1!
But Mount Nool is that way.
但是努雷山在那下
To the top of Mount Nool! As fast as lightning! Away, I go.
朝努震山顶前进 ! 快如内志 !
You'll be fine. Just think healing thoughts.
你不会有事的 只要专心实想自己恢复健康
-Horton! Look! -Horton! Look, look, look!
一荷顿 ! 荷顿 ! 一荷顿 ! 你看，你看 !
We've all got our own clovers with worlds on them!
我们全都有载著小世界的首蓄花
Yeah.
对
In my world, everyone's a pony,
我的小世界里，全部都是迷你融
and they all eat rainbows and poop butterflies.
他们都吃彩灿，然后便便是蝴蝶
That's beautiful, Katie.
那真是太装了，上断蒂
In a really weird way.
叭然有点怪怪的
My world is called Jessica-land, and everyone worships Queen Jessica
我的世界叫沈西卡王国 大家都超崇拜兹西上证女王
because Jessica is so beautiful.
因为淋西卡很漂亮
Jessica, that was awesome.
兹西卡，那区起来棒采了
-Rudy! -Mom, be careful!
一路迪! 一小心点 !
My best friend Thidwick lives on that.
我好朋友席克住那上面
Rudy, no one lives on this. It's not possible.
路迪，没人住在这上面 这是不可能的
That Horton is a menace.
那个荷顿真可显
Mom, Mom! Please, you're so weird. Don't do this to me.
嫣 1 拜斌，别这样
Horton!
荷顿 !
It's good!
射门得分 !
What do you think you're doing?
你到底在干嘛?
You guys with worlds are in trouble!
你们有有大麻闫了 !
-Have you forgotten what we discussed? -Oh, no. I'm an elephant,
一你忘了我们之前封论过什么? 一记得，我是大象
and elephants never forget. It's a curse, really.
大象从不忘记，这是个诅咒 !
l remember I was on my head, and you said “Humpf,"
我记得克哼了一声
and I looked up, and you said, “What are you doing?"
“你到底在干乳3”
And I said the thing about the speck.
我膏了灰庆的事
Then you pulled my ears and you poked me in the forehead...
称拉我耳薪，又惟我的额头…
-Horton! -Well, you did.
一荷顿! 一没错，动手了
Give me that clover, Horton. Now!
把那杀首著花给我，马上给 !
No.
不要
No?
不要?
Yeah.
对
Are you sure you want to fight this fight, Horton?
你厂定你要跟我作对 ?
Because I promise you it will get very ugly, very fast.
我可以跟你保证 到了时候场面一定很难看
And you need to ask yourself,
没多入你就会并始问自己
“Dol really want to put myself through all this?
“我干嘛要把自己摘成这样 ?
“For a clover?”
“就询了一双首著花2”
You don't.
你没注意职
So hand it over!
快把它交出来 !
No! I can't give it to you.
不要 ! 我不能把它给
There are people on this speck.
这粒灰应上有住人
Granted, they're very small people,
难然他们个子非常小
but a person's a person, no matter how small.
但历物生而平等 不论他们有多渺小
You just crossed the line, Horton, and I'm gonna make you pay.
你太元谱了，荷顿 我会让你付出代价的
That Horton is a menace.
那个荷顿太危险了
He has those kids using their imaginations.
他害这和群孩子整天胡思乱想
It's sick.
太可显了
All right, gotta get this speck up to the top of Mount Nool, ASAP,
好吧 ! 我得快点把这粒灰大 放到山顶去，要“快马加对”
whatever that means. Probably, “Act Swiftly, Awesome Pachyderm.”
叭然我不是马 但人家这丧象也能过河
I mean, how hard can that be?
那有什条困难的?
It's just a straight plummet to certain death.
只不过是条…保证摔死大象的桥
This looks kind of precarious.
这看起来有咒…不太坚固
Well, no need to worry.
先不要咕自己
Obviously, when they build a bridge like this,
他们当初建这人条梅的时候
they take into account that elephants will be crossing here.
一定有想过有一天会有大象走过
All right. Feels good. I'll just get the feel of it!
很好，膛不错 我就稍微给它…试试看 !
That's true.
没钳
Oh, God.
嗅，天啊
Hello. And how are we today, Mr. Mayor?
你好，今天好吗，镇长先生?
Say, "Ah."
说 : “啊”
Rinse, please.
请激流局
I think a few of these boards could stand to be replaced.
这里有些木板也早该换了吧
I just need to think light. I'm light as a feather.
我要想像我很码
I'm light as a feather!
到杜杜的…羽毛 !
Heavy feather.
好重的羽毛
Okay, this will just pinch a little.
这针只会有一中点痛
I'm lighter than a feather. What's lighter than a feather?
我得比羽毛还码 有什么比羽毛还轻?
Air! There's nothing lighter. So it stands to reason
空气 ! 没有比它轻的了 所以这就表示
that the more air I have,
只要我吸入愈多空气
Next, please.
下一位，请进
All right, that was absolutely terrifying.
真是听死人了
If I just pull myself up!
现在我得把自己拉上去
Try not to panic.
不要太罕张
That could've been a disaster.
刚刚差一束就双起来
Wow. I feel really good right now. Maybe it's my new sense of purpose.
“肢踏实地”的感觉还真棒 让我有股想跳舞的征动
All right.
没事了
Hey, JoJo! I need your help. Can you help me?
和在在 ! 我需要你帮忙，有空吗?
Okay, great. Okay. First, ! need you to go to the girls' room.
很好 首先，你先去姊妹们的房间
Take down Hanna's china doll collection and then...
把汉娜的陶痪姓姓拿下来
Stop looking at my arm.
别盯著我的手看
Put away Holly's light bulb collection, and then...
再把荷莉范集的灯泡收好
You know what? Just take care of anything that might break or shatter.
把容易壤或容易碎的东西全收好
Okay, take a good long look.
好吧，我就让你一次看个豹
Got it? Thanks, JoJo!
看欧了吧 ? 谢 ! 儿子
Here. And... Take that. And...
这些…选有那个…
Hi. You're home late.
老公，今天比较上晚嘿
Sorry, hon. I was just having some dental work done on my arm.
抱攻老路，我列是去牙医那里 处理我的…手
So, what was...
发生什条…
Ned!
奈德 !
What are you doing?
你在做什条了?
What do you mean?
栎指的是?
Well, I'm no detective, Ned, but you are hanging from the chandelier.
我不是侦探，不过你持在吊灯上
I just thought it might look better
我只是想把它移天一点
somewhere it can't fall on us and crush us in our sleep.
免得我们晚上睡觉时被砸到
What is going on?
到底怎订回事?
Hey, hon,
老改
did you ever get the feeling that you were being watched?
冻有没有过一种感觉 好像有人盯克看?
Yeah, sure. I suppose.
对啊，我想是有吧
And then you get the feeling that maybe that thing watching you is
要是娩知道一直盯著你看的那信估
a giant elephant?
是焦…超大的大象呢?
And you know how you get that weird feeling
要是有人跟代这冻的世界
that your world is actually a tiny speck?
层然是在一粒小灰麻上呢?
And that the elephant that I talked about earlier is carrying it around on a flower.
而我列才提到的那焦大象 秽把灰靡放一采花上
And you realize that if you tell anybody, they'd think you were crazy.
难然你很清楚克要是说出来 大家一定会认为你首了
But you still feel a responsibility to keep everyone safe.
但娩还是觉得 娩有责任保障大家的安全
You know that feeling?
称知道那种感觉吗 ?
You know, I'm gonna have to say no.
我想我应该不知道
Do you know that feeling?
你知道那和邦感觉吗 ?
No.
才不啊
Yawn. Wow. I am beat. Time to hit the hay, I guess.
真累，我想我该上床睡觉了
Sweetheart, I know you're under a lot of stress,
亲爱的，我知道你最近压力很大
and if you're seeing elephants and flowers, then fine.
所以就算你看到了大象和风采花 那也不错啊
Just don't tell anyone else that story, okay?
只是不要把这些事告诉列人
And remember, it's not the end of the world.
别坊了，这闪不是世界末日
“The end of the world.”
“世界末日”
Horton to Mayor. Horton to Mayor. Come in, Mayor. Over.
呼叫镇长，获到请回答，完举
Horton?
荷顿?
I get terrible reception here.
我这和里收讯不太好
How about this? If l get up real close, can you read me?
人这样呢 ? 我用力喊，你区得到吗?
Yep! Roger that.
有1 收到了
Are we at that safe place yet?
我们到安全的地方了吗?
Almost. I'm pretty sure the worst part's over.
就快到了 我想最困难的关卡已经过了
This is your elephant speaking.
这是大象荷顿的报告
Just sit back, enjoy the ride, and we'll have you to Mount Nool in no time.
我薪带各位前往努雷山 请好好享受这趟旅程
No, you can't have ice cream for breakfast.
不行，不能拿冰淇淋当早餐
-Please.
一拜旗
Who's that?
那是谁?
Is there someone else there?
那庄还有列人吗?
Well, that's my wife and kids.
那是我太太…膛有小芒
You have a family.
你还有家人
I do, indeed. A beautiful wife, 96 daughters, and one son.
没钳，我有个漂亮老亚 九十六个女儿，还有一个儿子
Oh, busy guy.
你还真行啊
And we all share one bathroom. You know how that is.
我们还共用一问遍所，你懂吧
Yeah. Don't I know it.
当然，共用离所嘛 !
Bathroom?
高所?
-Ned! -What?
一奈德 ! 一什订?
Sweetheart, you know you're on the roof, right?
亲爱的，你知道你在屋顶上吧?
-Please, Mom. -What's that?
一拜斌，妈嫣 一什订?
No, you need to go to bed. Daddy's having a breakdown.
不行，快上床睡党 答爸今天精神不好
Ned, what are you up to now?
奈德，你现在又怎样了?
I was just about to put the kids to bed when I got off the roof.
我正打算下去哄和孩子睡党
And that's what happened. Right.
事情就是这样，没钳
-Daddy? -Yes.
一苞和爸? 一什订?
-Can I have a glass of water? -Of course.
一你能不能手我倒杯水? 一没周题
-Me, too. -Me, three.
一我也要
Me, 28.
我也要
Okay.
好吧
Hey, JoJo!
和在在 !
A lot of liquid. A lot of liquid. Just the person I wanted to see.
好多好多杯水啊 和还遇见我想要遇见的人
Yeah, I realize that we have not been seeing eye-to-eye lately,
最近我们父子意见总是相左
and most of it is my fault.
大部份都是我不对
It's true.
没钳
You know what I've been trying to do?
我一直都一意孤行
I have been trying to impose my vision of your future on you.
要你照我的想法去规划你的未来
Let me make this perfectly clear.
让我好好跟你解释清楚
JoJo, you can be whatever kind of Mayor you want to be.
备厅，你想当什么样的镇长都行
Hands-on, strong and silent, outspoken, it's up to you.
积极、稳重、直率 哪一逢都行
Well, good. I feel so much better.
很好，我感觉好多了
lam expecting big things from you, young man. Big things.
我期待看到你有所成就，儿子
All right. Good night.
晚安
Good stuff. Good talk.
很好，就这样
Then JoJo snuck out, feeling lonely and sad,
接著备在溜出去，他孤单又难过
and tragically misunderstood by his dad.
难过父亲竟然这魔不了解自己
And where was he going at such a late hour?
他这麻晚了要去哪里呢?
Up te Whoville's abandoned Star-Studying Tower,
他跑到呼呼镇记计的天文公上头
a place where the boy felt contented, free.
这里让他感到自在又满足
A place he could be what he wanted te be.
这壬让他能随心所欲
And what was inside there, I'd say if 1 could.
那里闫有什么，先让我实个关子
Can I come out now, Mom?
我可以出来吗?
No, Rudy. Stay in your room.
不行，路迪，待在你的房间壬
-But, Mom... -Stay inside.
一但是… 一在里头待好
Mr. Vladikoff?
维拉考夫先生
Eating. Go.
吃饭，滚
Yes, l realize you're busy, but I need your help.
我知道你在吃大餐 但是我需要你帮忙
It's Horton.
那个荷顿
He's become obsessed with a clover.
他最近被一条首著给迷理了
And he actually thinks there are little people on it.
他还幻想那上面有住人
I want that clover destroyed.
我要你把首著给做了
Sure. What a big deal this is for you, bro.
小事，欠难需要用牛刀吗 ? 你自己动手吧
I'd do it myself, but being a lady, I prefer not to get my hands dirty.
我本来想自己动手 但身为贵娩，我才不想弄器手
But I hear you have no problem with that.
不过我事访你从不嫌手购
No.
对
No problem. Easy peazy.
没问题，简单得很
But I will only do this for a price.
但那也得看你的诚意
No.
不
This little kangaroo.
我要这焦小袋秘
-Mom! -Quiet, Rudy. Mommy's thinking it over.
一妈! 一安静，媚味正在想事情
Well, thanks, but on second thought,
谢了，经过我仔细考目
I think I'm going to have the Wickersham brothers
我还是找猴子音图
take care of this for me.
帮忙好了
Yeah, of course, Wickersham. I mean, they're a classy operation.
很好，找他们，他们人多劳办
You know, they do... Wait! No! You can't go with Wickersham!
不 ! 栋不能找他们 !
No, no, no, the Wickershams would be perfect for this job.
不、不、不… 这件事让猴子们来处理最通合
But they're monkeys! Is not scary!
那群策猴子，连都嘛不死人
Thanks, anyway. Maybe next time.
还是谢谢你，下次再说吧
Wait!
等等 !
Here is what I will do to precious clover.
我会这样对付那采首蒂花
and I will devour it.
最和后再一口知掉它
Bigger than it look.
这比想像的大
One second.
等一下!
Holy moly.
我的杂呀 !
Hang on.
先等一等
Then I regurgitate it.
之后我再把它吐出来
Then I'm going to devour it second time!
然后我会再把它给吞下去 !
So, two times devoured.
所以总共是吞了雨次
Sounds nice, but I think I'll talk to the Wickershams.
匠起来不锚 但是我想先找猴子们谈谈
Wait!
等等 !
Here is best part.
现在刚好在做促销
That's free, bro.
这可是免费的
What do you think?
栋觉得如何?
Yes! Score. Thanking you. You won't regret.
好耶 ! 搞定，感谢人 这次是做口碑的
Mayor!
镇长 !
Open up, Mr. Mayor! Mr. Mayor!
快肝门，镇长先生 !
It's snowing! In the summer!
下坟了 ! 现在是夏天 !
Yes. Yes, it is.
没钳，真的下雪了
It's a dramatic change in the weather,
气候出现喜天性的变化
as if we were a speck, floating through space.
我们就像一粒空中的小灰麻
I don't know how you knew, but somehow you did,
我不知道你是怎麻知道的 但全被你说中了
and Whoville is headed for disaster.
现在呼呼镇即兰面莉一场大炎难
Horton.
天哪，荷顿
What?
什条 ?
Nothing. I'm on it.
没事，我来处理
It's up to us to save the people of Whoville.
膏是我们皇救呼呼镇的时候了
You're small, but there are a lot of you!
你们蕉然还小，但人很多耶 !
That's it.
真是的
Okay, anybody else?
好了，和后面迁有吗 ?
Good.
很好
No, no. No enjoyment. This is not fun. It is a sign of doom!
这不好玩，这是末日的征兆 !
Aw, sweetie, that's...
疯爱的，真是…
No, no, no! Danger! Danger!
不 ! 危险!危险!
Stop having fun immediately!
立刻停止一切玩乐的行为!
This is dangerous! Okay!
这样真的很危险 !
Stop it!
停止 !
Horton!
荷顿 !
Hey, Mayor.
镇长
We're in big trouble down here.
代苑大人条了叭
It's happening! It's snowing in the middle of summer.
夏天才过一半居然下雪了
It's the end of the world!
世界末日到了 !
Hold on, Mayor. I think I know what your problem is.
等等，我大概知道问题出在哪里
There. That better?
现在好一点没?
That seems to have worked.
效果还多不错的
Do I smell peanuts?
好像有花生的味道?
Yeah, they're my favorite snack, but they tend to linger.
对 ，那是我最爱吃的是心 但味道会散不掉
Finwick, no!
粤实裤，不!
Hang on, Mr. Mayor. I may have to put up a fight.
等一下，人镇长先生 我想有人来找夺了
A frightened elephant can be very dangerous!
一焦受得的大象是很恶怖的
All right! You've called down the thunder, buddy!
这可是你自己找的唾，老兄 !
You hungry for trouble? I'm an “All you can eat" salad bar! Take a bite!
想找夸 ? 我可是加足马力了 ! 有种来吧 !
I hate running.
我讨厥跑步
Morton!
摩登 !
Don't do that.
不要嘿我
Horton!
荷顿 !
Horton! There you are!
荷顿 ! 你在这壬 !
We got trouble! Wait, stay, wait! Did you hear that?
有麻闫了 ! 你有隐访吗?
No, I'm here, okay. Listen. No! Go! Kangaroo has gone nuts, bananas.
不，惑我说 袋筷妈杂，已经发疯，脑袋壤了
She's telling everyone that you should be kicked out of Nool.
她告诉大家要把你中出努雷和森林
She said that? I thought we were her friends.
她那样这 ? 我还以为我们是朋友
Word is she's gone to Vlad!
职这她去找了维拉 !
Is it the bad Vlad or the bunny Vlad that makes the cookies?
是那个壕的维拉 和还是会烤饼乾的兔子维拉?
Yeah, Horton, she's sending you a bunny with cookies.
她最好是会派兔子送饼乾给你
I think we can assume it's the bad Vlad.
用膝盖想也知道是壕的维拉
Yeah, that's a good call.
对，那样才会理
So unless you're cool with giant, razor-sharp claws
所以除非你能忍受 那允心狠手辣多残的臭爪子
ripping the flesh off your body, I'd get rid of the clover!
把你的身避撕成碎片… 快把花给丢掉吧,
I can't! promised the Mayor.
不可以 ! 我答应过镇长
I meant what I said, and I said what I meant,
我这到做到…做不到就不访
and an elephant's faithful, 100%.
我们大象的忠诚度是百分百
Please. For me, just this once. Be faithful 99% of the time.
拜旗，为了我，就这魔一次 串诚度做到九十九分就好了
I've never gotten 99% on anything, and I think I'm awesome! So, come on!
我从来没拿明九十九分 但我还是很棒的 !
I meant what I said, and I said what I meant.
我遵守承诺，一言既出噩马准…
I'm not gonna say it.
那我就不追了
You can do that all day, it's not happening.
不过你材忙一整天也没用
An elephant's faithful, 100%.
大象的串诚…
That's right. That's my code, my motto. But thanks for the warning.
没钳，那是我的原则、座右钞 谢谢你提醒我
Motto. Okay.
座右铭，好吧
But watch the skies.
但是要留意天上
Keep watching the skies!
一定要涌盯著天空 !
Mayor, you need to get everyone underground.
镇苹，快通知所有人躲好
Now!
快!
1 don't want to sound the alarm,
我痊不想发出警报
but there's a good possibility we may be attacked
但我们极有可能会遭到一焦
-by a giant carnivorous bird. -What?
一大型肉食性高闫攻击 一什订?
There's a small chance it could be a bunny with cookies, but ! wouldn't count on it.
也有可能是会遇上送饼乾的兔子 但我想机会不大
They are formidable.
那真是太可怕了
Mayor? Are you there?
镇长，你在吗?
Yeah. No. That's a great idea. It's just...
在，那真是个好主意，只是…
In order to get everyone mobilized, I'd need the okay of the City Council,
如果要让大家动起来 我必须取得镇议会批准
and they never listen to me.
但他们内不青隐我这
I've been called a boob,
他们还叫我策蛋 !
several times. I can't do it!
叫了好多次，我办不到 !
You have to talk to them, Mayor! Okay. Listen.
你必须警告他们，人镇长 !
Bad Vlad!
壤的维拉 !
That is definitely not a bunny.
那绝对不是送饼乾的锡子
Lost him. Meant to lose him, and I lost him. Good.
有思掉他了 我想思掉他，就思掉他了
Is this tree for real? Come on!
这枯真性事 !
Hang on, Whoville! This is gonna get rough!
抓守了呼呼镇 ! 这下麻烦大了 !
Now you're going to get it!
准备好受死吧 !
Get ready for the best!
让你见识一下高手 !
Leave me alone!
天我速一点 !
Horton!
荷顿 !
I just know he's gonna jump out somewhere.
他一定会从某个地方跳出来
Hello.
哈唆
Chess mate.
投降吧,
Now it's time for me to take clover
现在让我把首蔷花拿遇来
and crush all the little people on it, who are saying...
毁了上面所有的小小人…
Sorry. This is where we get off.
抱火，我们先从这里下去了
Right in the beak!
丰子下了啦 !
Cool line. Usually I can't think of those things till later.
漂亮 ! 我的头脑还真才光
-Mayor? -Horton.
一镇长 一荷上顿
Are you okay?
你没事吧 ?
Well, more or less. What happened? The bird?
还好，怎麻回事?那高呢?
Yeah, it attacked me. Mayor, your people are in danger.
他啊，他居然攻才我 镇巷，你的镇民现在有危险
You know what? I'm gonna do it.
我打算这磨做
I'm going to go out there and tell them what is going on.
我要告诉大家发生了什么事
Perfect. Now, quick. Get going.
太好了 ! 快，事不宜肥
Hey! Mr. Mayor! Something's wrong!
镇长先生 ! 不太对劲啊 !
-My basement's in the attic. -The Science Museum is history.
一我的地下室变成关楼了 一科学博物馆全毁了
-The lost and found is missing. -What's going on, Mr. Mayor?
一失物招领处不见了 一到底怎庆了，人镇长先生?
I'm declaring a state of emergency!
我要宣体进入罕和急状态
Don't worry! Don't worry!
没事的 1 列担心 !
The Mayor is just being a moron.
镇长他只是在要和白阁
No, wait! Whoville is in terrible danger!
等等，呼呼镇现在非常危险
Everyone needs to get down to the underground storage area immediately.
所有人都该立刻躲进地下室计准
Fine! Fine!
好吧 1 好吧 !
Let's do this democratically.
我们就用民主的方式解决
Who wants the joy and glory and festivity
有谁希望看到呼呼镇 伟大光荣的百年庆
of the Who-Centennial to proceed as planned?
要计划进行?
Yeah!
好耶!
And who, like the Mayor,
又有谁和镇长一样
thinks it would be better to spend the Who-Centennial
认为最好能在黑漆漆的地下室里
in an underground storage area?
度过呼呼镇百年庆呢 ?
Yeah!
好耶!
Our whole world could explode!
我们的世界可能会爆炸妈沽
Much more quickly!
比这快多了
And our world wouldn't make that noise.
也不会发出这种怪声
The people have spoken, Mr. Mayor.
人民已经作了决定，镇长先生
You're finished. No one believes you.
你已经完蛋了，没有人相信你
No one supports you.
也没人支持你
Horton believes me.
荷顿就相信我
Horton?
荷顿?
Who's Horton?
谁是荷顿?
Horton is a giant elephant in the sky!
荷顿是…在天上的一焦大象
Don't bother looking, he's invisible.
不用找了，他是隐形的
And he's the one risking his life to get Whoville,
他正冒著生命危险拯救我们
which, by the way, is a speck on a clover, to safety!
让落在花采上小灰庵里的呼呼镇 得到安全
I can prove it!
我可以证明
Horton's voice comes out of this horn.
荷顿的声音会从这喇叭传出来
Horton!
荷顿 !
I have all the Whos gathered in town square!
我已召集所有人民到广场集合
Let them know you're there!
让他们贡隐你的疡音
Gee. This is kind of a high-pressure situation, then.
天，原来沼公办人物压力这魔大
Wow. l am really drawing a blank here.
我还真不知道该这什么
I know!
我知道了
Horton!
荷顿
Horton, we're waiting!
荷顿，快点啊!
Time to show everyone that you exist,
是时候该向大家证明你的存在
and by extension, what a non-boob I am.
顺便这明白…我绝对不是策蛋
Wait!
等等 !
Everyone, look at the wind. What do you think that that means?
大家看那个风 你们以为那代表了什条 ?
It means, obviously...
那很明普地是代表…
Let the kite-flying race begin!
放风笔大赛现在开始
What a burn on you, Horton!
看看你有多丢脸，荷顿
Brain freeze.
啊…有入冰的
Give me back my speck!
把花和还给我
Not this time, guy.
就差一点，可异
lam so sorry that I let you down, but this... This is bigger than me.
我真的很抱儿让你失望 但是这比我自己重要多了
Get the family together and get somewhere safe.
带和孩子们找个安全的地方租好
I will! l believe you.
我会的 ! 我相信你
I've got you now, elephant.
这下看你怎订玩，大策象
No, no, no!
不要丢…不要 !
Oh, no!
不
Mayor?
镇长?
Anybody there?
有人在家吗 ?
Hello?
哈唆?
Anyone?
有人吧?
But clover by clover by clover, he found
荷顿他找过了一采又一采
that the one he sought for was just not around.
逢怎麻也找不到他要找的那一采
Mayor?
镇长?
Hello?
哈唆?
And by noon, poor Horton, more dead than alive,
直到中午，可情的荷顿精疲力
had picked, searched and piled up 9,005.
他找过的九千零五采花 己堆成许多花堆
Hello?
哈唆?
Sorry to bother you,
抱歉打摄到你了
nobody.
没人
Knock, knock.
殴殴有门
This is where you'd say, "Who's there?"
这时候你该这 傈“和象”啦?
if there were any Whos there.
如果你在的话
Get it? "Whos there.”
职懂没?傈“象” 咏!
All day he looked, looked on and on,
他整天不停的找
until his hope was almost gone.
直到他已鸡乎放豪希望
No, no, no! Please, no!
不…拜斌,不要 !
This isn't fair!
这样不公平啦 !
But, wait, could this one be the one?
等一下，扒道会是这一条吗 ?
Was all his searching finally done?
他千辛葛苦要找的就是这采 ?
Ah, yes, for this was the hour.
是的，皇天不负善心人
Horton had found them on the three millionth flower.
荷顿终於找到了 就在这三百多韶采花之中
Mayor! Mayor!
镇长 ! 镇长 !
I found you!
我找到你了 !
Mayor?
镇长?
Are you there?
你在吗 ?
Mayor.
镇长
Mayor, are you there?
镇长?
No, this is Floyd.
不，我是佛洛德
Can I take a message?
你要留话呆?
Mayor! You're okay!
人镇其 ! 你没事了 !
Horton! Horton! Stop! Stop it!
荷顿 ! 列乱动 ! 停下来 !
Sorry.
抱攻
lt must have been rough down there. l can't believe found you.
你们下面列刚一定很履 真高机你们没事
You really had me worried.
我都快担心死了
Say! The Mayor was right!
老天 ! 镇长先生是对的
Daddy! Daddy! Daddy!
备爸 1 答符 ! 答和爸 !
Okay, I'm all right, and so are you.
好了，我没事了 裤上由女儿栋们也是
Citizens of Whoville!
呼呼镇的镇民们 !
I'd like you to meet our friend Horton.
见过我们的朋友荷顿
He's going to help us!
他会帮助我们
I've got this.
交给我吧
This is the Chairman...
我是议会主席…
Idiot!
白泛 !
You're finished in this town! Is that understood? Finished.
你完蛋了 ! 区见没? 订物 !
You boob!
大笨蛋 !
I'm just joking.
引你开玩笑的啦
Good one.
很好笑
Horton, this is my wife Sally.
荷顿，这位是我太太，莎莉
You exist!
你真的存在 !
Hooray!
好耶!
And a few of my daughters, Haley, Holly, Hooly, Hilda and Hedy.
和还有我鸡个女儿… 海莉、荷莉、胡莉、海达和海萌
-Hi!
一你好
And here is Miss Yelp, my loyal assistant.
和还有业波小姐，我最得力的助手
-And here's Dr. Larue. -You saved us!
一接著是拉鲁博士 一你救了我们 !
And Burt from accounting,
会计部的伯特
and Mrs. MeGillicuddy, and Mr. Farfoogan
梅洁莉寇迪太太和法福根先生
from the Clugan Farfoogans,
他来自克鲁格法福根
and the old man in the bathtub.
和还有在浴和后泡深的老头
Let's not overwhelm the poor fellow.
别折磨他了
He's never gonna remember all these names.
他不可能记得所有名字的
Sally, Chairman,
落莉、主席
Haley, Hooly, Holly, Hilda, Hedy, Miss Yelp,
海莉、胡莉、荷莉…波小姐
Dr. Larue, Burt from accounting, Mrs. McGillicuddy, Mr. Farfoogan
拉重博士、会计部的伯特 梅兹莉寇迪太太、法福根先生
of the Clugan Farfoogans, and wasn't there an old guy in a shower?
是不是有个老头在洗深?
Bathtub.
泡深
-Yeah! -We're all here, Horton,
一噢，差一点 ! 一我们全都在这里，荷顿
and we all believe in you.
和还有…我们全都相信你
Wow. That's awesome.
那真是太棒了
And it's a responsibility I do not take lightly.
我对於你们的承诺绝对不打折
I promise you a future that is safe, sound and stable.
我保证你们会有一个 安稳又健全的未来
We will create a world where every Who is endowed with three inalienable rights,
我们要并制一个世界 让大家都有国民年金绥老农津赂
to be determined at a later date.
这是我们接下来必须做的
And we will put a speck on Mount Nool before the end of this decade.
我们要把这糙小小的灰麻 在十年之欠放到努震山上去
This elephant is crazy! Oh, my goodness.
这焦大象首了 ! 我的老天第
I gotta tell everybody. I need to get to the Kangaroo.
我得告诉大家，我要找袋所嫣嫣
Wait till they find out about...
等到他们发现就…
You should have been seeing me. I really let elephant have it.
称该看看当时我有多猛 我狠儿教训了那焦大象
I chase him, I torment him, I break him into million little elephant pieces.
我追击他、折魔他 把那焦大象撕痫成又百万个碎片
It was thing of beauty, really. My best work. Classic Vlad.
我这次干得漂亮，真的 最例落的一次，维拉代表作
And the clover?
那采首某花呢?
Clover is finished! No way in million years Horton find it.
它早毁了 ! 荷顿别想找到它 !
Read my beak. Clover is gone forever.
读我的饥嘴，首著花已经微底完蛋了
I just saw Horton, and he is still talking to that clover!
我刚看到荷顿还在跟那洒花说话
Idiot!
大人饭桶
Whoa! Come on, I'm your bro! It's me you're talking to. We have history!
我是你兄弟，炼谈心的好对象 我们都是老朋友了
Come on, let's not forget, I did this for free!
别访了这一切还是免费服务
What is happening to the jungle of Nool?
和努震森补到底出了什么问题?
There once was a time when people were people
这守以往都是居民刀导民
and specks were specks.
小灰麻电小灰摩
Well, l say, “If you can't see it, hear it or feel it,
那看不到、阴不到或感觉不到的
“it doesn't exist!"
根本就不存在 !
Our way of life is under attack!
我们的生活模式正受到破壕
And who is leading that attack? Horton!
这是谁造成的? 荷顿 !
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
学1党1学!
Wait a minute! This is Horton we're talking about.
先等一等 ! 现在访的是荷顿吗 ?
You all know him, he wouldn't hurt a fly.
我们都认识他，他连屁都不天放
Except for that fly city he sat on. But he didn't do that on purpose.
除了那次把学生粳和悍之外 但他绝对不是故意的
Shut up, mouse!
于嘴，臭老鼠 !
That's weird. My brownies are burning. I gotta go!
当我没这，我的蛋薰快烤焦了 我该网了
Are we going to let troublemakers like Horton poison the minds of our children?
我们真的要让荷顿这个菩褐精 毒害芒子们的心志吗?
Not the children!
芒子是无幸的 !
When Horton tells our children about worlds beyond the jungle,
当荷顿告诉孩子们 关於兼补以外的世界
Which leads to defiance! Which leads to anarchy!
这致孩子们的叛弟 导致社会陷入混乱
Yeah! Horton must pay!
没钳，荷顿要付出代价 !
It's that speck!
都是小灰麻阅的褐
We have to do something!
我们必须探取行动
For the children!
为了和孩子们 !
Are we going to let him get away with this?
我们要让他就此中着法外吗 ?
No!
不
Let's go!
我们去抓他
Morton! I told you! 100%!
摩登 ! 我这过，大和象最讲信用 !
Horton!
荷顿 !
Morton, pick up your feet! Jeez.
摩登，脚步碍轻一点，真是的
It's not me!
我没那磨重 !
I see. It's an angry mob. Sorry, Morton.
我知道了，是一群暴民
I thought it was you that was making all the...
我还以为是你…
But it's...
不过这个…
Oh, darn.
天啊
Run, Horton!
荷顿，快跑
There he is!
他在那里 !
Let's rope him!
把他狠起来 !
Let's cage him!
把他关起来 !
No! No! No!
不!不1不!
Stop!
停 !
Hey, fellas. Good to see you,
各位，大家好
all at once.
全都到计了
You look really great as a horde.
你们还真声劳浩大啊
Horton, Horton, Horton,
荷顿、荷顿、荷上顿
look at the mess you've created for yourself.
看你为自己又造了多大的麻闫
All this hullabaloo over a silly little flower.
全都是为了那采小春花
It's a speck.
是一粒灰庆
Right. mean, it's silly, really, all this talk of roping you,
随便，这真是策透了 这蠢东西害你被五花大贱
and caging you, and, well, we don't need to go into the details.
还要被关起来…不用膏那磨清楚
The point is, this angry mob, all the trouble you're in,
和还有你捅造的一切麻闫
it can all go away.
全都能一笔勾消
-Really? -Of course.
一真的? 一常然吐
All you have to do is admit to everyone that there are no little people
你只需要向大家认错 承认那粒小小的灰庆上
living on that speck.
痊没有住人
You do that and things can go right back to the way they were.
照我这的去做，一切就能回电正
But if you don't, you're going to have to pay the price.
但如果你不肯，你就准备付出代价吧
So, I just have to say it isn't true?
只要说一切都是假的就行了?
Go ahead. Rope me, cage me. Do whatever you want.
动手吧，贱我、关我 你们想怎样都行
But there are people on this speck.
但是灰麻上真的有住人
And they have a Mayor, who has 96 daughters and one son named JoJo,
他们还有镇苹，他有96个女儿 和一个叫乔奋的儿子
who all share a bathroom, whatever that is,
他们共用一问认所…管它是什么
and even though you can't hear or see them at all,
难然你们贡不到也看不到他们
a person's a person, no matter how small.
葛物生而平等，不论他们有多四小
That was beautiful, Horton.
说得可真动区，荷上顿
Rope him! Cage him!
贱住他 ! 关起来 !
And burn that speck in a pot of boiling Beezlenut oil!
把那粒春灰鹿丢到滚温的热油里去
They don't believe we're here.
他们不相信我们在这壬
We've got to make some noise!
我们必须又造点声音 !
We are here! We are here! We are here!
我们在这、我们在这、我们在这
Come on!
大志叫 !
-Everybody! -We are here! We are here! We are here!
一大家一起叫! 一我们在这 ! 我们在这 ! 我们在这 !
We are here! We are here! We are here!
我们在这 ! 我们在这 ! 我们在这 !
This will teach you not to make up stories about people on specks!
这次教训是要告诉你 不要编那种灰庆上有人的故事
Listen! There they are!
你们贡 ! 他们在这祷 !
-Rope him. -Cage him!
一铺住他 一关起来
It's not working.
声音还不锡大
I can hear you, but their ears aren't strong enough.
我区得到，但他们职力不锡好
We need to be louder!
我们必须大声一点
Get every Who to make noise! Everyone!
大家都来稻造嗓音，一起来 !
We are here! We are here! We are here!
我们在这 ! 我们在这 ! 我们在这 !
JoJo! Where are you going?
和在奋 ! 你要去哪里?
We need every voice! JoJo!
我们需要所有人的声音 ! 备奋!
You need to make some noise down there, or we'll all be destroyed!
声音必须再大一琶 不然我们都完了 !
The Mayor grabbed a tom-tom and started to smack it,
镇长抓起了一对鼓梭 开始用力的打超来
and all over Whoville, they whooped up a racket.
呼呼镇上上下下 全都卵足全力呼喊
They rattled tin kettles! They beat on brass pans!
他们拿出锡锅、敲打黄铀平底例
On garbage pail tops and old cranberry cans!
脚跌垃圾桶和破饭镶
They blew on bazookas and blasted great teats.
他们改奏低音喇叭和大喇叭
On clarinets, oompahs, and boompahs, and flutes!
还有蔷稍、巴松和长箭
There!
荷顿 !
Can they hear us now?
他们现在职得到吗 ?
Listen, please. It's the most beautiful thing ever.
快孤啊，求求你们 这是我聘遇最美妙的疡音
I don't hear nothing!
我什么也没娶到
I don't think so. But keep trying.
我想是没职到，继续试下去
I'll never give in!
我绝对不放素
Are you sure that every Who down in Whoville is trying?
你确定每个呼呼镇民 都有台力丢造声音吗 ?
We are here! We are here!
我们在这 ! 我们在这…
Where's JoJo?
和在备人呢 ?
Probably at the old observatory.
大概又跑到普天文人台去了
Hey! There's a limit!
不要太过份了
That's not supposed to stretch that far!
我的鼻子弹性没那麻好
JoJo!
和在在 !
You built this?
这些是你做的?
We are here! We are here! We are here!
我们在这 ! 我们在这 ! 我们在这 !
You're making a mistake.
称大锚特钳了
But, Mom!
但是，杂 !
This doesn't concern you, sweetie. Back in your pouch!
这不干你的事，回你房间去 !
Everybody! Don't stop!
大家注意 ! 别停 !
Keep going! This is gonna do it!
大家继续，这次一定有用 !
We are here! We are here! We are here!
我们在这 ! 我们在这 ! 我们在这 !
Can they hear?
他们贡到没?
No!
没!
No matter what happens, I couldn't ask for a better son.
不管最和后结果如何 你都是我最棒的儿子
Hey, JoJo!
和在在 !
Come on! Keep going!
继续，不要放率 !
No!
不!
We are here! We are here! We are here!
我在这里 ! 我在这里 ! 我在这里 1 …
Yopp!
哺!
I hear it! I hear it!
我匠到了 ! 我隐到了 !
They are there!
他们在那里 !
And that Yopp, that one small extra Yopp put it over,
而那一声呼喊 那一融小小的呼喊衡破天际
and all the Whe noises burst out of the clover.
所有呼呼族的声音从花上传出来
-l hear it! -Me, too!
一我了贡到了 一我也是
Rudy. Give me that! Come...
多子，把花给我 ! 拿来…
Rudy. Get back in the pouch. Now!
儿子，快回到袋子里，葡话
No, Mom.
不要，杂
Wickershams! Get that clover!
猴子们，把那采花拿来
Anybody! Take it from him!
谁都可以 ! 把花拿台来 !
You did it, Mayor. You did it.
你成功了，人镇长，你成功了
We did it!
我们成功了 !
Yeah!
耶 了
Well done, son.
干得好，儿子
All right, Mayor!
干的好，人镇长
Dad, you're one of the greats!
老爸，你进入名人党了
Whoa. Easy, everyone! Easy!
大家别激动，慢慢来
Hi, Vlad.
你好，维拉
Well, ! shouldn't, but...
其实我在减肥，管他的
Oh, man, that is nice touch.
这一刻可真感人
lam a mess with this, right? Emotional! Here come the waterslide.
我想我太感动了，对吗? 我太情钞化，眼省要决提了
There's so many people to thank.
我要感谢很多人
The good people of Nool,
谢谢努震的好居民
who put me in a cage and poked me with sticks.
把我关进定实还用棍子惟我
That was me!
惟他的就是我 !
My buddy Morton, for being the only one who stood by me.
我的兄弟摩登，一直支持著我
Well, not right by me.
也不算支持啦
He hid in the bushes, sending me good thoughts. He's small.
他诅在草玉里帮我出主意，他很小
Dude, you are a warrior poet.
老兄，你还真是文武全才
whe believed in me from the beginning.
他从一开始就相信我
Horton, we're going to miss you.
荷顿，我们会很想念你的
What are we gonna do without you, Horton?
荷顿，少了你我们该怎订办 ?
Don't worry. I'll always be around.
别担心，我会永速守访你们
And even as I wander
即使我在外流浪
I'm keeping you in sight
我仍设法看顾你
You're a candle in the window
你是窗畔的烛火
On a cold, dark winter's night
照亮冰冷黑暗的冬夜
Beautiful metaphor.
真美的比喻
And I'm getting closer
而我比我想像中
Than ever thought I might
更靠近你
That's a little high for me.
这音调高了一点
I've forgotten what I started fighting for
我已忘记我是在抗拒什么
And if l have to crawl upen your floor
就算我得番外在你脚下
Crawl upon the floor
番外在你脚下
Come crashing through your door
撞穿你家大门
Baby, l can't fight this feeling anymore
我再也扰法克制…
And so all ended well, for both Horton and Whos,
从此荷顿和呼呼族 以及森补里所有动物
and for all in the jungle, even kangaroos.
其至袋鼠妈妈，都过得幸福美满
So let that be a lesson, to one and to all.
这件事教学我们每一个人
A person's a person, ne matter how small.
葛物生而平等，不论他们有多四小
Yeah, I like this. Faster, more up-tempo.
我喜散这样喝，快一点
I've forgotten what I started fighting for
我已忘记我是在抗拒什么
It's time to bring my ship into your shore
是时候该让我这稻船停千克岸头
That's a metaphor!
好比喻 !
And throw away the oar
抛开船业
Another metaphor!
又一个比喻
And buy an engine
买个引擎
‘Cause I can't fight this feeling anymore
我再也扰法克制…这份情感
From the weight of my trunk to my toes
从头到脚
I've forgotten what I started fighting for
我已忘记我是在抗拒什么
Well, you shouldn't be fighting anything. Enjoy yourself.
你不该抗拒什条，享受人生
If l have to crawl across the floor
就算我得番外在你脚下
-Now, break down your stupid door -Crashing through your door
一撞穿你家那遍灿门 一撞穿你家大站
On an empty stomach
空著肚子怎麻克制
I'm just saying words.
我随便乱喝的啦
That felt so good. Cathartic!
喝歌的感觉真好，真是太爽了
What?
怎样?